Hi. I'm Sue.
I'm a technical program manager
for Google's support platform.
A technical program
manager is responsible
for making sure the team
delivers on what
it sets out to do.
That means pulling together
a lot of different
capabilities and
deliverables coming
from across many teams
to pull together a product
that we deliver to our customers.
Without customers,
there's really no reason
to be building anything.
And what's interesting about building
projects and working with
customers and trying
to imagine what they want,
is it puts you in this
really unique place
where you need to put
yourself in their shoes
and imagine the world or
imagine the product
through their eyes.
In a project management role,
being able to empathize and
understand how different
people in the world will
interact with your
product is really
important and gives you
this amazing perspective.
Understanding the
customer's needs
is a very difficult job,
but it's really important.
I believe it's a skill you
can develop over time.
I actually consider a customer
just a certain kind
of stakeholder.
I like to take my stakeholders
and group them into buckets,
so I have customers,
and they are usually
the end users of a product or
the ones that are
purchasing the product.
And then I have stakeholders
that are sponsors,
rather—the people that are funding
the team that's
actually building this.
Those two groups of people
are very different, and I like
to treat a sponsor in
a very special way.
They are looking to increase
their return on investment,
and so you always need to
be looking for ways to
quantify, how are you
generating a return
on that investment?
There's always this little fear
that they're not going to
get what they paid for,
and giving them
information frequently
and at the right
level of detail is
a really important skill to
have as a project manager.
Sometimes you can
overwhelm them with
too many details and they
cannot see the forest
through the trees,
and sometimes you
don't give them enough
detail, and they don't
trust what you're
telling them. And so
striking that balance
is really important.
I really enjoy seeing
a project from
the very beginning to the
very end, when you actually
get to show it to a customer and
get their acknowledgment and
recognition and see
their excitement
at seeing the product
actually working;
something that, when
you just started,
there was nothing—just
ideas and maybe some papers.
Then, however many months
later you actually have a
product that you can show off.
What I love about project
management is it puts you in
that role, so you can really
see things from the
beginning to the end.